9

Anton Tugaenko

Software Engineer with a Background in Physics

□ anton@tugaenko.com

****** +44 7937 969279

in tugaenko

Amsterdam, Netherlands

Me

Software engineer specialized in Python, with almost 7 years of experience and a background in experimental physics. Passionate about teaching software engineering fundamentals to adult students as a part-time role. Currently seeking a full-time position in Amsterdam to apply my skills and experience.

Experience

Software Engineer @ Positive Technologies (infosecurity solutions), web application firewall backend team (January 2021 – July 2022)



- Developed features called 'user rules' and 'black/white lists'
- Sped up several slow handlers up to 10 times by profiling, refactoring and query optimizing

Stack: Python, aiohttp, PostgreSQL, Rabbit MQ, gRPC, NGINX, k8s etc.

Tutor (part-time) @ <u>Yandex.Practicum</u> (bootcamp), mentors' team. Actually, it's a hobby, but they pay me. (since December 2021)

Yandex

• Grow students from zero to market-fit backend developers

Stack: Python, Django, SQLite, PostgreSQL, NGINX, Docker etc.

Software Engineer @ Yandex.Taxi (online ride-sharing service), b2b backend team

Yandex

(July 2018 – January 2021)

- Produced a lot of typical backend business-related tasks including:
- Took essential part in <u>business-account release</u>
- Prettified customer connection processes, developed a drastically simplified process for a new clients' registration. Ten times less fields to fill —> higher conversion

Stack: Python, aiohttp, MongoDB, PostgreSQL etc.

Junior Software Engineer @ Iponweb (ad-tech company), main server team

IPONWEB

(October 2016 – July 2018)

- Designed Video Ad Serving Template library (Lua)
- Refined and speed-up native ads library by performing O(n log n) match instead of O(n²)
- Lead a project of reworking of all server-side Lua code to get rid of global scope pollution

Stack: Lua, Perl, MongoDB etc.

Self-Educator @ home

(July 2016 – October 2016)

Udacity, Coursera, Codecademy, Google for developers etc. Prepared myself for a career pivot

Lead Engineer Physicist / Product Owner @ Inkram (gas analyzers developer), R&D dept

ИНКРАМ

(February 2011 – June 2016)

- Managed a team of engineers and workers. Supervised the development of complex technical devices, including one of the company's main product lines
- Led several industry-related research projects. Adapted prototypes for mass production

Engineer Physicist @ MEPhI (National Research Nuclear University), laser physics lab

(May 2005 – February 2011)



- Scientific work. Research, papers, conferences and so on. Mentored students
- Played a key role in development of explosives gas analyzer based on FAIMS and laser ionization

Education and Scientific Work

• PhD in Laser Physics | June 2010 | National Research Nuclear University "MEPhl"



- Masters in Solid State Physics | February 2006 | National Research Nuclear University "MEPhl"
- 17 programming courses completed on Coursera, Udacity, etc. | 2015 2016
- 5 patents and 15 scientific publications (all about physics and technology). | before 2015